Remember, our analytics need to be actionable.
记得吗 分析必需是可执行的
Oftentimes, we're moving away from looking at past data,
很多时候 除了关注历史数据
and starting to use the analytics process to evaluate what we need to be doing now.
我们需要开始分析和评估接下来的行动方案
Just like our hypothesis testing,
就像假设验证
the process of creating a brief,
分析摘要的撰写过程
gives us a way to study things in a focused manner to generate actionable insights.
让我们可以很专注地进行分析 从而得出一些可执行的想法或者洞察
The act of simply reflecting and studying your business as it exists now,
首先 要对当前的业务进行反思和研究
can be a really important analysis.
这个是很重要的分析部分
Now the business story lays out relevant customer segments to consider,
然后 我们可以得出有哪些目标群体可以考虑
and describes which ones to go after and why.
以及定位到哪个群体和为什么
Our business story is going to answer two questions.
我们的业务故事需要回答以下两个问题：
What relevant actionable segments do we have access to?
目前都有哪些相关的、可执行的客户群体？
Which ones should we pursue?
我们应该定位到哪个群体 为什么？
Now we'll talk in more depth about customer segments later.
我们稍后再详细讲客户划分
But ultimately, we're trying to evaluate where we want to take action.
最终 我们需要评估出在哪里采取行动
Marketing is really about changing the way someone behaves.
市场是一门研究如何改变人们的行为的学问
Our business story is about figuring out
而业务故事就要辨别出目标群体里哪些行为
which behaviors inside of a customer segment are going to be the easiest to change,
是最容易改变的
so they adopt the goal or the conversion that we want them to take.
趋势他们进行转化 或者采取我们希望他们做出的目标行为
Let's go back to our hypothetical grocery store.
还是以超市为例
Let's say that we've been asked by senior management to
比如说 上级要求我们
look for ways to increase revenue and reduce costs.
提高收入 减少开支
Honestly, this is really the most frequent asked,
讲实话 这个要求是最常见的
it just often comes flavored differently.
只是具体表述可能不同
So we start by figuring out which segment of
因此 我们需要搞清楚哪些客户群体
our customers will bring us the best opportunity to take action.
会呈现出最高的可执行性
We know from the biometrics,
从海盗模型可以知道
that we're looking at our daily numbers.
我们需要每天都关注指标数字
So we're going to see customer lifetime value.
那这里 我们可以关注客户终身价值
So we will be very familiar with what that value is.
我们需要知道当前的 LTV 是多少
Now we're going to come to learn later that we can
稍后我们会学习到
actually model that value by segment, we'll get there.
实际上可以根据客户群体划分来给出不同的 LTV 但这是后话
But for now, if we know that we can increase the lifetime value of our customer,
目前 我们只需要知道可以通过提高 LTV
that'll get us one step of the way towards increasing revenue.
来提高收入 所以提高 LTV 是第一步
So we look and determine that the most actionable segments of customers that we have,
假设 我们根据数据 发现最具执行性的客户群体是
are those that have a high affinity for sports.
那些喜欢运动的人群
We know that they frequent the store for snacks such as soda, chips, and dips.
他们经常会来超市买零食 比如苏打水、薯片等
We know that these are our highest margin items.
而这些是高利润产品
We may also have another customer segment that has a high affinity for say, fitness.
还有一类客户群体 喜欢健身
Their frequenting bottled water and sports drinks,
他们经常来买瓶装水、运动饮料
also high margin items.
这些也是高利润产品
These are our highest and most relevant segments.
所以 这两个是我们最相关的、最具执行性的客户群体
So from here, we need to analyze which segment we should pursue.
接下来 我们要分析到底定位到哪个人群
Are we going after sports or fitness?
运动人士 还是 健身人士？
Well, if it was right after the New Year,
如果是新年过后
we might choose fitness.
我们可能会选择健身人士
Why? Well, because it's going to be the most actionable,
为什么？因为大多数人的新年愿望可能都跟健身有关
most people are making New Year's resolutions about their fitness goals.
所以健身人士是当前最具可执行性的群体
If we're coming in a football season with the superb months away,
如果快到橄榄球赛季 距离超级碗还有几个月
we might identify that this is the most actionable segment.
那么运动人士会是我们的目标人群
You see what we're doing here? We're thinking outside the box.
你能看出我们在做什么吗？我们跳出了框架之外
We're applying insights from the world around us,
将周围生活的点滴纳入到分析中
not just the analytics toolkit that we have in front of us.
而不是仅仅依靠分析工具
So let's say, that we're going in the football season.
假设 现在是橄榄球赛季
Now we know that we're going to be targeting sports enthusiasts,
运动爱好人士是我们的目标人群
because we're going to want them to buy more drinks.
我们希望让他们购买更多饮料
Again, we always want to understand the action that we're going to be steering.
我们可以更具体地来理解我们希望他们采取的行动
So we need them to buy more sports drinks,
所以 我们希望他们购买更多的运动饮料、
more soda, and more chips.
苏打水以及薯片
So there's our hypothesis.
这就是我们的假设
We hypothesize that we can increase our revenue if we
即 如果可以影响运动爱好人士的购买行为
influence the behaviors of this sports enthusiast segment.
我们就可以提高营收
We also need to actually decide by what value we can increase revenue.
现在 我们需要量化提高营收的目标
As we know from how we set smart goals,
从 SMART 原则可以知道
we need to have something that's measurable.
我们需要可量化的目标
We can help arrive at that value as we move through this brief.
不要着急 随着分析摘要的逐步完整
You'll see how later,
我们会在测试与学习环节
when we move to the stage of testing and learning.
学到如何量化目标
The overall goal here, is to think about the narrative elements.
综上 我们需要通过业务故事来讲述一个完整的故事
What story can we tell about our business,
这个故事要关于业务
through the customers or the target markets,
客户以及
that we have immediate and actionable access to?
可执行的目标群体